Guide to the Munford-Ellis Family Papers, 1777-1942
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Munford Family; Ellis Family; Munford-Ellis Family; Tucker family; Talbot family; Ellis, Powhatan, 1790-1863; Munford, George Wythe, 1803-1882; Munford, Thomas Taylor, 1831-1882; Brady, Mathew B.,ca. 1823-1896; Johnston, Joseph E.(Joseph Eggleston),1807-1891; American literature -- Virginia; Appomattox Campaign, 1865; Cabinet photographs; Carte de visite photographs; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877)--Virginia; Confederate States of America -- History, Military; Virginia -- Genealogy; Mississippi River Valley -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Virginia -- History -- 1775-1865; Virginia -- Intellectual life; United States -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives, Confederate; Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849; Jackson, Stonewall, 1824-1863; Five Forks, Battle of, Va., 1865; South Carolina.General Assembly; Virginia Military Institute -- History -- 19th century; University of Virginia -- History -- 19th century; Photograph albums; Black-and-white photographs; Cartes-de-visite; Cabinet photographs
Contents of Collection
- George W. Munford Division: Correspondence Series, 1786-1942, (9 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1786-1834 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1835-1848 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1849-1858 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1859-1862 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1863-1867 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1868-1875, June (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1875 July-1881 May (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1881 June-1888 Aug. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1888 Sept.-1942 and undated (Box 9)
- George W. Munford Division: Miscellaneous Series, 1781-1885 and undated, (4 boxes)
  - Essays and speeches (Box 9)
  - Poems (Box 10)
  - Novel manuscripts
  - Genealogy
  - Photographs
  - Clippings (Box 11)
  - Maps
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1832-1849
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1850-1885 and undated (Box 12)
  - Religious notes
  - Legal papers, 1781-1867
- Thomas T. Munford Division: Correspondence Series, 1777-1925 and undated, (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1777-1898 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1899-1909 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1910-1925 and undated (Box 15)
- Thomas T. Munford Division: Miscellaneous Series, 1806-1902 and undated, (5 boxes)
  - Legal papers, 1834-1902 (Box 15)
  - Printed materials (including obituary of T.T. Munford)
  - Clippings and printed material (Box 16)
  - Virginia flag and Seal papers
  - Speeches: Confederate Veterans (Box 17)
  - Narrative history of 2nd Virginia Calvary, including diaries of Confederate officers, Rosser-Munford dispute
  - Diary of James D. Ferguson
  - Miscellaneous Civil War notes
  - Miscellaneous history writings and transcripts (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials
  - Virginia Military Institute papers
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes on the Battle of Five Forks, 1865 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence (77 items), 1806-1893 and undated
- Volumes Series, 1772-1912, (24 volumes)
  - Ellis, Charles: Account book, 1823-1826 (Volume S:1093)
  - Ellis, Charles: Letterpress copybook, 1856-1893 (Volume L:1097)
  - Ellis, Charles: Memorandum book, 1808-1809 (Volume S:1098)
  - Ellis, Charles, Sr.: Account of Estate Administration by Thomas Harding and Charles Ellis, Jr., 1847-1848 (Volume F:1095)
  - Ellis, Charles, Sr.: Family Bible (records), 1772-1898 (Volume M:1096)
  - Ellis, Charles, and Thomas Harding: Account of Administration of Estate of Charles Ellis, Sr., 1841-1853 (Volume S:1094)
  - Ellis, James Nimmo: Commonplace book, 1835 (Volume M:1099)
  - Ellis, James Nimmo: Notebook, 1838-1839 (Surveyor's) (Volume M:1100)
  - Munford, Charles Ellis: Notebook (Law), 1859-1861 (4 volumes) (Volume M:3050, M:3051, F:3052, M:3053)
  - Munford, George Wythe: Account book, 1835-1865 (4 volumes) (Volume F:3055, F:3056, L:3057, F:3058)
  - Poems and Account book, 1821-1837 (Volume F:3059)
  - Munford, Lizzie Ellis: Scrapbook of Poetry, 1860-1871 (Volume ff:3054)
  - Munford, Thomas Taylor: History of the Battle of Five Forks, 1865-1916 (copy on microfilm) (Volume M:3061)
  - Munford, William: Account book, 1799-1873 (Volume F:3062)
  - Munford, William: Miscellany, 1790-1814 (Volume ff:3063)
  - Talbott, Sallie (Munford): Scrapbook, 1877-1912 (2 volumes) (Volume M:3831, L:3832)
  - Munford-Ellis family photograph album, 1860-1890 (Box 20)
- Oversize Material Series, 1848, (1 folder)
  - Munford, Thomas T.: Certificate for the election of Presidential Electors in Quincy Township, Franklin Co., Virginia, Nov. 7, 1848 (Opaperfolder 1)